SERGEI DANILOV

Flutter Developer

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Helsinki

Finland

PHONE

+358 40 5580107

EMAIL

gigok100@gmail.com

SKILLS

Flutter

Dart

Android

iOS

Firebase

Material Design

LANGUAGES

__

English

Russian

Finnish

PROFILE

Experienced mobile developer with 6 years of dedicated expertise in crafting Android, iOS, and Web apps using Flutter and publishing them into the app stores. Committed to creating top-notch applications by prioritizing clean, readable code and exceptional user experiences.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

__

Mobile developer, Freska Group Oy
Oct, 2020 — Present

Helsinki

- Developed a mobile application for service workers of the cleaning company from scratch in an impressive amount of time, reducing administrative burden, improving efficiency by providing information on-the-go, and enhancing communications.
- Productively optimized the existing mobile app, leading to an improved customer experience, increased user satisfaction, and enhanced app performance.
- Successfully created a dedicated package for shareable code and UI library components, resulting in accelerated development and enhanced component testability. Additionally, designed an interactive demo page using Flutter web to showcase these components, further improving accessibility and usability.
- Improved the CI/CD pipeline scripts with GitHub Actions, which led to an average 38% decrease in the time needed to build and deploy the app.
- Optimized the mobile application for different devices and screen sizes, resulting in improved usability and more pleasing visual experience.

Jun, 2017 — Apr, 2020

- Created and maintained user-friendly responsive web and mobile apps for real estate agents using Angular/HTML/CSS and Flutter.
- Developed and maintained RESTful APIs using C# language and .NET Framework with Microsoft Dynamic CRM-system integration.
- Incorporated third-party APIs into the applications for data exchange and real-time updates.
- Assisted and trained other software engineers as a team lead.

EDUCATION

Bachelor, NUST "MISIS" Sep, 2014 — Jun, 2019

Moscow

The field of Information Systems and Technologies.

The topic of the graduation thesis: "Algorithmic and software support for a mobile application for interaction with an electronic library system".